Guide to the Helen Halbig papers, 1937-2010 MS2326
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Helen Halbig papers
1937-2010
1941-1991
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Halbig, Helen
MS2326
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Helen Halbig (1914-2010) worked for the Public Housing Administration from the late 1930s to 1972, and aided in the creation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. During WWII she volunteered with Civil Air Patrol and as a trainer with American Women's Voluntary Services. Helen was also involved with the Alexandria chapter of the League of Women Voters (LWV) and served on their board of directors. This collection contains paper records of Helen Halbig's work with the Public Housing Administration, as well as paper documents related to her personal life, including her work with the League of Women Voters. The materials date from 1937-2010.
Box 2
Box 1
Biographical Note
Helen Halbig (November 22, 1914 - March 10, 2010) worked for the Public Housing Administration from the late 1930s to 1972, and aided in the creation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. During WWII she volunteered with Civil Air Patrol and as a trainer with American Women's Voluntary Services. Helen was also involved with the Alexandria chapter of the League of Women Voters (LWV) and served on their board of directors.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains paper records of Helen Halbig's work with the Public Housing Administration, as well as paper documents related to her personal life, including her work with the League of Women Voters. The materials date from 1937-2010.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Vincent Novara, 22 April 2014 (2014.008).
Arrangement
Organized into 2 series: Work records and Personal life
Public health; Housing; Women -- History; Alexandria (Va.); United States. Department of Housing and Urban Development; Halbig, Helen
- Work records, 1937-1984; Series 1; 0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains paper documents related to Helen Halbig's career with the Public Housing Administration including employment records, correspondence, reports, and notes, as well as training and award certificates.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Employment Records (1/2), 1937-1950; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Employment Records (2/2), 1951-1972; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Work Records - Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins, and Notes (1/2), 1940-1943; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Work Records - Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins, and Notes (2/2), 1944-1971; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Material Presented to Unit Meeting for Housing Consensus, 1984 March; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Training and Awards Information and Certificates, 1956-1971; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Personal life, 1941-2010; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet 1 Box
  This series contains paper documents related to Helen Halbig's personal life including her work with the Alexandria chapter of the League of Women Voters, and her research into mental healthcare. Also included is information about her death such as funeral programs and her obituary.
  - Agendas for Alexandria League of Women Voters (LWV) Board Meetings [1/2], 1981 January 11 - 1983 November 1; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agendas for Alexandria League of Women Voters (LWV) Board Meetings [2/2], 1984 February 7 - 1987 June 2; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - League of Women Voters of Virginia Handbook Binder [1/2], 1986 September; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - League of Women Voters of Virginia Handbook Binder [2/2], 1986 September; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Material Related to Alexandria League of Women Voters and their work in Alexandria, 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Material Related to Mental Health Care, 1941-1991; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal Life Records - Obituaries, Funeral Programs, Birthday Announcement, 2004 October, 2010 March; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)